Cage McGehee Johnson

cagejohnson.com 830-613-1712 cagejsn@gmail.com



Cage is an *outcome oriented* Senior Software Engineer with 6 years professional software experience. He brings a creative perspective to technology organizations. His wide technical knowledge allows him to function accurately in any area of a technology product, and his interpersonal skills enable him to influence others and drive change within organizations. He has a track record of leading teams to meet their goals and pushes the team to focus on what matters most for the big picture.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin | May 2017 Bachelor of Business Administration Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Experience

Senior Consultant - Slalom Consulting April 2018 - Present

While at Slalom, I was a client-facing consultant. My primary responsibility was delivering projects. Additionally, I managed 3 direct reports and led our internal volunteering organization.

Client Projects:

Canonical Data Model for Multi-National Corp.

- Contributed to development of a system giving a "Canonical" view of Customers in a business with hundreds of CRMs.
- Reduced bad merges by building a test for our Database Migrations.
- Enabled Team to hit critical milestone by debugging persistent public cloud networking issues and memory consumption issues.
- Led design of a configurable, data-transforming, python application.

Customer Data Platform (A "Bring your own Data" marketing product)

- Led Engineering Team for a re-design of a Customer Data Platform Architecture your that was too complex and became
- Influenced Architecture for the hyper-configurable ETL at the heart of a the product.
- Designed and built all CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab CI including Code Quality integrations.
- Designed and built Integration Tests which would stand as acceptance of completed milestones.

Billing for a Global Digital Advertising Product

- Led the Engineering Team to design and deliver a major change in tax accounting rules, including changes in several applications and requiring backward & forward compatibility.
- Contributed to a re-platforming of mission critical billing ETLs from on-prem Oozie to cloud-based Airflow.
- Modernized a suite of java applications from Spring / Tomcat to Containerized Spring Boot.
- Improved QE & deployment processes by building pipelines and tools to automate error-prone manual tasks.

Native iOS app leveraging ARKit

- Contributed to design and development of an app for AT&T's "field engineers" which allowed them to 3d scan and annotate AT&T owned assets.
- Identified ARKit optimization which allowed us to store bigger ARKit "Scans"

Quality Assurance Engineer - Mutual Mobile September 2017 - April 2018

- Authored & executed Test Plans for a custom mobile app.
- Implemented bug fixes in Java for Android mobile app.

Founder - Desk August 2016 - May 2017

 Led a team of software engineers to design, develop, and sell an app on Apple's App Store.

Leadership Experience

Division Leader - Camp Champions May 2017 - August 2017

- Led 12 counselors to ensure an excellent camp experience for 150 twelve to fourteen year old campers.
- Communicated with parents and collaborated with counselors to aid in camper's character development.
- Planned and coordinated age group specific activities.

Director - Longhorn Entrepreneurship Agency May 2016 - May 2017

- Acquired dedicated space on campus for a student-run entrepreneurship space.
- Led effort to raise \$16k for on-campus entrepreneurship space.
- Coordinated the Fall UT Austin Startup Job Fair with 350 student attendees and 18 startup participants.

Awards & Honors

- Eagle Scout Boy Scouts of America
- Friar Society The University of Texas at Austin
- Cleanest Business, TOPGUN College Works Painting

Technologies

Python: Advanced
Java: Advanced
Golang: Advanced
Bash: Advanced
git: Advanced
Docker: Advanced
TypeScript: Intermediate
AWS: Intermediate
GCP: Intermediate
Vue: Intermediate
Django: Intermediate
PostgreSQL: Intermediate
Airflow: Intermediate
SQL: Intermediate

Skills

Backend Engineering
Frontend Engineering
Quality Engineering
Data Engineering
Public Cloud Architecture
Data Modeling
Monitoring
CI/CD
Stakeholder Communication
Prototyping
Infrastructure as Code
Agile & Scrum

Product Design

Engineering Team Lead